{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"butterflies and moths","incorrectAnswers":["animal diseases","the effect of light on chemicals","the historical study of languages"],"question":"What is Lepidopterology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Beginning","incorrectAnswers":["The End","Between Courses","With A Soup"],"question":" At which stage of a meal would you have an hors d'oeuvre?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Saint Kitts and Nevis","incorrectAnswers":["Andorra","Liberia","Switzerland"],"question":"Basseterre is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Britannia","incorrectAnswers":["Albion","Roma","Britanica"],"question":"What was the name the Romans gave to Great Britain?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Shells and molluscs","incorrectAnswers":["The Weather","The origin and spread of diseases","Sex"],"question":"What is conchology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Joaquin Phoenix","incorrectAnswers":["Peter O'Toole","Roger Moore","Alan Cumming"],"question":"Which actor has played iconic roles in both Gladiator and Joker?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Alicia Vikander","incorrectAnswers":["Jennifer Jason Leigh","Rooney Mara","Rachel McAdams"],"question":"Who won the 2015 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress for playing the role of Gerda in The Danish Girl?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Cleopatra","incorrectAnswers":["Hatsheput","Nefertiti","Nitocris"],"question":"Who Was Ptolemy Dionysius Related To As Both Brother And Husband?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Kimono","incorrectAnswers":["Cheongsam","Sari","Hijab"],"question":"What is the Asian-style robe that is often used as a dressing gown?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Joyce","incorrectAnswers":["Samuel Beckett","Oscar Wilde","Jonathan Swift"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Finnegans Wake'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Prada","incorrectAnswers":["Armani","Gucci","Versace"],"question":"What is the last name of the Italian fashion designer Miuccia, who works for her family's fashion house & founded its sister line Miu Miu?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Venus","incorrectAnswers":["Jupiter","Mercury","Mars"],"question":"Which is the hottest planet in the Solar System?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cells","incorrectAnswers":["Genetics","War","Hair"],"question":"What is Cytology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Farrow","incorrectAnswers":["A Larva","A Caterpillar","A Codling"],"question":"A young hog is known as what?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Beijing","incorrectAnswers":["Hong Kong","Shanghai","Guangzhou"],"question":"What Is The Capital Of China?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Madonna","incorrectAnswers":["Eric Clapton","Nicki Minaj","Alanis Morissette"],"question":"Which American singer released the album 'Confessions on a Dance Floor'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Play it, Sam. Play 'As Time goes By.'\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"That’s a bingo!\"","\"Look at me. I’m the captain now.\"","\"Who's on first.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Casablanca'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Gerard Butler","incorrectAnswers":["Hugh Jackman","Robert Redford","Jim Carrey"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including 300 and James Bond: Tomorrow Never Dies?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Queen","incorrectAnswers":["Feeder","The Clash","Pink Floyd"],"question":"Which British rock band released the single 'Another One Bites the Dust'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Salem","incorrectAnswers":["Greensboro","Alexandria","Wilmington"],"question":"In Sabrina The Teenage Witch What Is The Name Of Sabrina's Cat?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Et tu, Brute?","incorrectAnswers":["Veni, Vidi, Vici.","Carpe Diem!","Memento Mori?"],"question":"What are commonly believed to be the last words of Julius Caesar?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The twenty first","incorrectAnswers":["The third","The fifth","The eighteith"],"question":"What amendment to the u.s. constitution ended prohibition","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Cartilage","incorrectAnswers":["Tendon","Ligament","Muscle"],"question":"What part of the body, often referred to as 'gristle', is important for the formation of bones?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Brass","incorrectAnswers":["Woodwind","Percussion","Stringed"],"question":"What type of instrument is a bugle?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"2015","incorrectAnswers":["2000","1993","2004"],"question":"In which year was the creation of the first artificial heart?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Neptunium","incorrectAnswers":["Francium","Plutonium","Americium"],"question":"What is the atomic number of the first transuranium element?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Schiller","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Intrigue and Love'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Peanuts","incorrectAnswers":["Lentils","Black beans","Chickpeas"],"question":"Which of these is a major food allergen?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Profiterole","incorrectAnswers":["Strudel","Kringle","Cannoli"],"question":"Which of these desserts is a ball of choux pastry filled with cream?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alice Munro","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","E. T. A. Hoffmann","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Family Furnishings: Selected Stories 1995-2014'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Cria","incorrectAnswers":["A Baby","A Lamb","An Infant"],"question":"What would you call a baby llama?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Vinegar","incorrectAnswers":["Aspirin","Lemon Juice","Soap"],"question":"Acetic Acid Is More Commonly Known As What?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Enrico Fermi","incorrectAnswers":["Joseph Lister","Nicolaus Copernicus","Constantine the Great"],"question":"Which influential physicist created the first nuclear reactor?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"James Abbott McNeill Whistler","incorrectAnswers":["‎‎Edvard Munch","‎Pablo Picasso","Diego Velázquez"],"question":"Which artist painted \"Whistler’s Mother\"","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Police","incorrectAnswers":["The Rolling Stones","U2","Ultravox"],"question":"Which band had Sting as its lead singer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Afroasiatic","incorrectAnswers":["Sino-Tibetan","Austronesian","Turkic"],"question":"The language 'South Levantine Arabic' belongs to which language family?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Nellie Melba","incorrectAnswers":["Esmerelda Tiramisu","Fannie Brulée","Bridget Treacle"],"question":"Which Opera Singer had a dessert named after her?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Nonagon","incorrectAnswers":["Octagon","Hexagon","Septagon"],"question":"What is the name of a shape with nine sides?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Let","incorrectAnswers":["Dus","Par","See"],"question":"What 3 Letter Word It The Name Given To A Replayed Point In Tennis?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Smile","incorrectAnswers":["Grin","Laugh","Cry"],"question":"Which legendary Beach boys album was never completed?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Sally Ride","incorrectAnswers":["Joan Jett","Mary Winn","Ella Davis"],"question":"Who was the first female American astronaut?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Fear and Loathing in Las Vegas","incorrectAnswers":["On the Road","Blood Meridian","Catch-22"],"question":"Which Hunter S. Thompson book involves a wild journey through the desert and a series of autobiographical stories?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Susan Sarandon","incorrectAnswers":["Kate Winslet","Helen Mirren","Maggie Smith"],"question":"Which actress has starred in in films including The Rocky Horror Picture Show and Fame?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Engels","incorrectAnswers":["Michael Ende","Erich Maria Remarque","Karl May"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Communist Manifesto'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Buckingham Palace","incorrectAnswers":["Windsor Castle","Kensington Palace","St. James's Palace"],"question":"What is the name of the London residence of the British monarch?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"The Usual Suspects","incorrectAnswers":["The Shining","Ghost","The Adventures of Robin Hood"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Roger \"Verbal\" Kint'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"1910","incorrectAnswers":["1810","1710","2010"],"question":"In which year did the Mexican Revolution begin?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Comfortably Numb\" by Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["\"Rapper's Delight\" by Sugarhill Gang","\"Welcome to the Black Parade\" by My Chemical Romance","\"Baby Got Back\" by Sir Mix-a-Lot"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"Hello? Is there anybody in there?\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"John Locke","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Baruch Spinoza","Jean-Jacques Rousseau"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'No man's knowledge here can go beyond his experience'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the song 'Walk On'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"1939","incorrectAnswers":["1915","1923","1931"],"question":"In which year was The Wizard of Oz released?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Golf","incorrectAnswers":["Table tennis","Swimming","Rowing"],"question":"With which sport is Tiger Woods associated?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Black Widow","incorrectAnswers":["Tarantula","Jumping Spider","Crab Spider"],"question":"Which Spider Devours Its Partner After Mating?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Bangalore","incorrectAnswers":["Christchurch","Beijing","Wellington"],"question":"Which of these cities is in India?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Fish","incorrectAnswers":["Meat","Vegetables","Fruit"],"question":"What is the English translation of the French word \"poisson\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Karl Marx","incorrectAnswers":["Epictetus","Friedrich Nietzsche","Martin Heidegger"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'Philosophers have hitherto only interpreted the world in various ways; the point, however, is to change it'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George Orwell","incorrectAnswers":["Joseph Conrad","Virginia Woolf","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Animal Farm'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Nomadland","incorrectAnswers":["The Father","Judas and the Black Messiah","Mank"],"question":"Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2020?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mannerism","incorrectAnswers":["Italian Renaissance","Baroque","Dutch and Flemish Renaissance"],"question":"The painting \"View of Toledo\" by El Greco is a part of which art movement?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Pink Floyd","incorrectAnswers":["Wings","Rudimental","The Alan Parsons Project"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Comfortably Numb'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Toulouse","incorrectAnswers":["Barcelona","Copenhagen","Amsterdam"],"question":"Which of these cities is in France?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Atmospheric dust and its effects","incorrectAnswers":["Life","Human culture","Dogs"],"question":"What is Coniology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Vatican City","incorrectAnswers":["Monaco","Nauru","San Marino"],"question":"What is the smallest country in the world?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Seven","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","White","Black"],"question":"In Spanish, what is the meaning of the word 'siete'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the song 'Master of Puppets'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Oak Tree","incorrectAnswers":["Fir Tree","Maple Tree","Elm Tree"],"question":"What type of tree is known for its large, dark green leaves?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Fourteenth","incorrectAnswers":["Twentieth","Tenth","Seventh"],"question":"In which century was The Black Death?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"measurement","incorrectAnswers":["the relationship of biological or other phenomena to their locations","spiders and their kind","wounds and injuries caused by accidents or assaults and their surgical treatment and repair"],"question":"What is Metrology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jack Vance","incorrectAnswers":["H. P. Lovecraft","Edgar Rice Burroughs","Ursula K. Le Guin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Planet of Adventure'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Carrie Underwood","incorrectAnswers":["Taylor Swift","Miranda Lambert","Faith Hill"],"question":"Which female country singer had hits such as 'Jesus, Take the Wheel' and 'Some Hearts,' and also won 'American Idol'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"India","incorrectAnswers":["Central America","Central Asia","Southeast Asia"],"question":"From which part of the world does mango originate?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Dominican Republic","Nicaragua","Honduras"],"question":"From which country do pre-embargo 1950s Romeo y Julietas, a type of cigar, sell for as much as $400 each?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Plant nutrition in relation to soil conditions","incorrectAnswers":["Existence","Dreams","Emetics"],"question":"What is Agrobiology the study of?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"L'chaim","incorrectAnswers":["Shalom","Mazel tov","Todah rabah"],"question":"What is the Hebrew phrase that is used as a toast to life or to good health?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ridley Scott","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Alien?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Metallica","incorrectAnswers":["Alice Cooper","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American heavy metal band released the studio album 'Master of Puppets'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Neptune","incorrectAnswers":["Jupiter","Uranus","Saturn"],"question":"Which planet has the longest orbit around the sun?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Escort","incorrectAnswers":["Beetle","Passat","Model S"],"question":"Which of these is a model of car made by Ford?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Operation Bagration","incorrectAnswers":["Operation Barbarossa","Operation Overlord","Operation Market Garden"],"question":"What was the name of the Soviet Union's counter-attack on Germany in 1944?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cuba ","incorrectAnswers":["Barbados","Jamaica","Trinidad"],"question":"Which Is The Largest Island In The Caribbean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Master and Commander","incorrectAnswers":["Pirates of the Caribbean","The Last Samurai","Gladiator"],"question":"In which period film did Billy Boyd serve as Russell Crowe's coxswain?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Bonnie and Clyde","incorrectAnswers":["The French Connection","Dirty Harry","The Godfather"],"question":"Which crime film from 1967 features Gene Hackman as Buck Barrow?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The United Nations","incorrectAnswers":["The European Union","The League of Nations","Interpol"],"question":"Which major international organization was created in 1945?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Hamlet","incorrectAnswers":["Macbeth","King Lear","Othello"],"question":"Which 5-act Shakespearean tragedy was partially based on a history of Denmark written by Saxo Grammaticus?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cuba","incorrectAnswers":["Mexico","Ecuador","Argentina"],"question":"With which country is Fidel Castro associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Crime","incorrectAnswers":["Human growth","Spiders","The color red"],"question":"What is criminology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"University of Michigan","incorrectAnswers":["Ohio State University","University of Notre Dame","Harvard University"],"question":"In which university was Gerald Ford voted MVP of the football team in 1934?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"L'Anse aux Meadows","incorrectAnswers":["Quebec","Hedgesville","Iceland"],"question":"What was the name of the Viking settlement that was established in Newfoundland, Canada?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Epicurus","incorrectAnswers":["Jean-Paul Sartre","Niccolo Machiavelli","Bertrand Russell"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'The greater the difficulty, the more glory in surmounting it'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Alchemists","incorrectAnswers":["Hussars","Chandlers","Smelters"],"question":"What type of people were obsessed with turning ordinary metals into gold in the Middle Ages?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Azan","incorrectAnswers":["Adhan","Quran","Iqama"],"question":"What is the name of the Islamic call to prayer?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Tell 'em to go out there with all they got and win just one for the Gipper.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"My precious.\"","\"Houston, we have a problem.\"","\"No wire hangers, ever!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Knute Rockne--All American'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Doors","incorrectAnswers":["Styx","The Pussycat Dolls","Three 6 Mafia"],"question":"Which American rock band released the studio album 'The Soft Parade'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Barbados","incorrectAnswers":["Timor-Leste","Morocco","Oman"],"question":"Bridgetown is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Andrew Johnson","incorrectAnswers":["John Adams","Thomas Jefferson","James Madison"],"question":"Who was the first president to be impeached?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Mikhail Lermontov","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolai Gogol","Mikhail Bulgakov","Alexander Pushkin"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Hero of Our Time'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Bread","incorrectAnswers":["Cheese","Fruit","Nut"],"question":" What type of food is pitta?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"KFC","incorrectAnswers":["McDonald's","Burger King","Wendy's"],"question":"Which fast food is known for a menu that mainly contains fried chicken?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Octave Mirbeau","incorrectAnswers":["François-René de Chateaubriand","Stendhal","Guy de Maupassant"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Diary of a Chambermaid'?","difficulty":"hard"},